skinnyscoop.com 2012-06-08

# SkinnyScoop | Privacy

Welcome to theSkinnyScoop! This is a website for moms and other women interested in related topics, offering a positive and engaging environment and a “sanity check” on parenting, products and more personal topics.

This privacy statement (“Privacy Policy”) covers theSkinnyScoop service (the “Service”) which is offered by The SkinnyScoop LLC (the “Company”) via our website at: [www.theskinnyscoop.com](http://www.theskinnyscoop.com/) (the “Site”). References to “we”, “us” and “our” herein refer to theSkinnyScoop.

At theSkinnyScoop, we are committed to maintaining your privacy and your trust. We are moms ourselves so we understand that you care about how your personal information is used and shared, and we take your privacy seriously. This Privacy Policy explains how we collect, protect, use and share information about you when you use the theSkinnyScoop Site. This Privacy Policy is incorporated into and subject to the theSkinnyScoop Terms of Service. Each time that you use the Site, you signify that you agree to be bound by the Terms of Service and this Privacy Policy. If you do not agree to the terms of this Privacy Policy, you must discontinue using the Service and terminate your membership.

This Privacy Policy does not apply to the practices of companies that we do not own or control, to people whom we do not employ or manage, or to third party websites. 

**INFORMATION WE COLLECT**

We collect user information in an effort to improve your experience and to communicate with you about our service.

**User Provided Information.**  
We collect personal information from you when you register with us, update your profile, interact with other members of theSkinnyScoop (“Members”), and use our various features. In order to register with us as a Member, you must provide your name, zip/postal code, gender and birthdates of any children, and email address. When you submit this information, we will send you a confirmation email to which you must respond in order to complete the registration process. Once you are registered, you will be given the option to add additional personal information about you and your family to your profile. Your information is not anonymous to us. However, by using the privacy settings on your profile, you can control which users have access to certain of your personal profile data. Certain basic profile data cannot be hidden and will always be displayed by us once you register, including your username and your geographic location.

All personally identifiable information that we collect may become part of your user file and may be used by us as provided in this Privacy Policy, as disclosed at the time you provide the information, or as otherwise agreed by you. We may also collect information about you under the following circumstances:

\- We may collect information regarding your interaction with other users and your use of the Service;  
\- From time to time we may ask you to respond to surveys or other requests for information from which we will gather the data you provide;  
\- We may collect information from you when you participate in sweepstakes and promotions offered through the Service;  
\- We may also collect information about you through other methods, including research surveys or information we obtain from third parties, including verification services, data services, as well as public sources. 

We use the information collected to continually offer you the most value as a user of the Service. 

**Information Explicitly Granted by Social Network Platforms.**  
If you access the Service on a “social network platform” (including but not limited to Facebook), we will access and store the information explicitly allowed by the social network platform in their Terms of Service, once you explicitly allow us to do so through an interface provided by the social network platform. As we do not have control over the user interface provided by social network platforms, we do not take any responsibility for any changes or problems with the interface or exchange of information provided by any of these social network platforms. 

**Web Logs.**  
Like most standard Website servers, we collect information from all visitors to the Site. This information may include the browser you are using, the internet address from which you linked to our Site, the operating system of your computer, the unique IP address of the computer you used to access our Site, and usage and browsing habits. We use this information to help diagnose and troubleshoot server malfunctions, to analyze trends, track user movement in the aggregate, and gather broad demographic information. We may also use individual information we collect through web logs to send you offers and other communications that may be of interest to you.

**HOW WE USE YOUR INFORMATION**

**Communications.**   
theSkinnyScoop may send you service-related announcements and emails from time to time. For instance, if a friend sends you a question or someone wants to “follow” your activity on the Site, you may receive an email alert from us. We may also use your information to send you e-newsletters, updates and communications about theSkinnyScoop. You may change your communications preferences by going to the “My Skinny” tab and clicking on “Settings” then on “Notifications.”

**Sweepstakes and Promotions.**   
On occasion, we offer sweepstakes and other promotions in conjunction with a sponsor. By participating in a promotion, you submit to that promotion's terms and conditions, which may allow us to share your personally identifiable information with a particular sponsor.

**Third Party Offers.**  
On occasion, we are able to offer you special products or services through a relationship with a third party. In those cases, the offer will be brought to you by theSkinnyScoop and fulfilled by the third party. If you accept the offer, you will become a customer of the company that is fulfilling the offer and we will not have control over their use of the personally identifiable information that you provide to them when you accept the offer.

**Third Party Ad Servers.**  
We may use third party advertising technology to serve ads when you visit our Site. For instance, we may use Google AdSense, among others, to provide advertising on our Site or in our e-newsletters. If your browser is set up to accept cookies, Google AdSense and other of theSkinnyScoop's advertisers and partners may place cookies or web beacons on your computer when you visit our Site or interact with our email messages. Please note that this happens whether or not you click on an advertisement placed by these companies. Google AdSense and theSkinnyScoop's advertisers and partners use cookies and web beacons according to their own privacy and security polices.

**SHARING YOUR INFORMATION**  
We do not sell or rent your personal information to third party companies or individuals, unless we have your consent. As described in this Privacy Policy, we may, however, share your personal information under certain circumstances without your consent, including:

\- To enforce our Terms of Service;  
\- To comply with legal requirements including but not limited to court order or subpoena or to prevent or investigate suspected fraud, violations of our Terms of Service, or activity that appears to us to be illegal or may expose us to legal liability we may, without your consent, access and disclose your information, any communications sent or received by you, and any other information that we may have about you or your account;  
\- In situations that we believe involve potential threats to the physical safety of any person or property, if we believe that your information in any way relates to that threat;  
\- In the event that theSkinnyScoop sells substantially all of its assets or a line of business, or is acquired or merged with another company, personally identifiable information of our Members may be one of the assets sold or merged in connection with that transaction. theSkinnyScoop will notify users of the Site of such a change in ownership or transfer of assets by posting a notice on the Site and emailing to the address you have provided us;   
\- To provide information to trusted businesses or persons for the sole purpose of processing personally identifying info; and  
\- With trusted third parties, marketing partners that provide services on our behalf or with whom we have collaborated to offer a particular service. We reserve the right to add, remove or change our marketing partners from time to time.

**COOKIES AND WEB BEACONS**  
To help make sure you receive information that is relevant to you, our Site uses data "cookies." These cookies are small data files stored on your computer which identify you as a previous visitor to the Site and help us to personalize your experience when you arrive. Most web browsers are set to accept cookies. You can instruct your browser not to accept cookies. However, if you disable this function, you will not be able to use some of the features on our Site.

Our Web pages and our e-mail newsletters may contain "web beacons." Web beacons allow us to count users that have visited a web page or opened an email that contains a web beacon and collect other types of aggregate information. Using this information, we are able to measure the effectiveness of our advertising and how visitors use our Site. This allows us to learn what pages are most attractive to our visitors, which parts of our Site are the most interesting and what kind of offers our Members like to see. Some of the web beacons that may be in place on our Site are used only by theSkinnyScoop, and other web beacons may be from our vendors and advertisers who use this data to assist us in analyzing how our Members use the Site. In addition, we may have agreements with various affiliate networks that promote theSkinnyScoop on their affiliate websites. These affiliate advertisers may use web beacons in their advertisements to track users who click through from the affiliate website to the Site.

**SECURITY AND CONFIDENTIALITY**  
theSkinnyScoop has multiple layers of security on its systems. We have implemented software and hardware security, including firewalls and data encryption intended to protect your personally identifiable information from unauthorized access. We use firewalls and intrusion-detection devices that are designed to defend against hackers and notify us if any attempts are made to compromise our network. In the event there is unauthorized access to your personally identifiable information, you acknowledge that theSkinnyScoop is not liable for any harm or damage that may result from this unauthorized access, and your use of the Site confirms that you assume this risk.

**CHILDREN**  
theSkinnyScoop does not encourage participation or visitation by children. The Service is not intended for children under 18, and we do not knowingly collect information from children under the age of 18. Children aged 18 or older should not submit any personal information without the permission of their parents or guardians. By using the Service, you are representing that you are at least 18 years old.

**GENERAL**

**Changes.**  
We may modify or revise this Privacy Policy at any time by posting notice of the changes at [www.theskinnyscoop.com/privacy](http://www.theskinnyscoop.com/privacy). We also will notify you via the email address you have provided us, so you must ensure that our email is not filtered out by your ISP or email software. You agree that your use of the Site (including your use of the Service via any other websites, applications, platforms, software or downloadable clients) after the date on which this Policy changed will be an indication of your acceptance of the update and that you agree to be bound by such modifications or revisions. You can always review the most current version of the Privacy Policy at: [www.theskinnyscoop.com/privacy](http://www.theskinnyscoop.com/privacy). 

I **nvite a Friend.**  
As a Member you may invite other individuals to join as a Member of the Site. Using the contact information you provide, we will send your friend a one-time email invitation to join theSkinnyScoop. We store this contact information for the sole purpose of sending the one-time email and tracking the success of our referral program. Your friend may contact us at: [support@theskinnyscoop.com](mailto:support@theskinnyscoop.com) to request that we remove this information from our database.

**Links to other sites.**  
theSkinnyScoop Site contains links to other sites that are not owned or controlled by us. Please be aware that theSkinnyScoop is not responsible for the privacy practices of such other sites. We may also provide links to our partners’ websites, through which you can access information about their services. Any data that you supply to these partners on their websites, is beyond our reach and will be the responsibility of each of the linked-to entities and not theSkinnyScoop.

We encourage you to be aware when you leave our Site and to read the privacy statements of each and every website that collects personally identifiable information.

This Privacy Policy applies only to information collected by this Site. We are not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of third party sites linked to or referenced on our Site.

**Your Submissions.**  
If you post any questions, answers, or content on the Site, you should be aware that any personally identifiable information you submit can be read, collected, or used by other users and could be used to send you unsolicited messages. We are not responsible for the personally identifiable information you choose make available on the Site.

**A Note About International Users.**  
theSkinnyScoop Site is hosted in the United States. If you are using the Site from outside the United States, by providing your information to this Site, you are consenting to the transfer of your information to the United States for processing and maintaining in accordance with this Privacy Policy and our Terms of Service. You are also consenting to the application of California law in all matters concerning this Site, as further described in our Terms of Service.

**Updating Your Personal Information.**  
If you are a Member of theSkinnyScoop, you can update your personal information at any time. To do this, just click on the "My Skinny" tab and go to “Edit Information”. You acknowledge that we are unable to update or delete any of your personally identifiable information that has previously been shared with a third party as permitted in this Privacy Policy.

**Questions.**  
This Privacy Policy describes the personal information we collect about you, why we collect it, how we use it and when we share it with third parties. If you have any questions about our Privacy Policy, you can send us an email to [support@theskinnyscoop.com](mailto:support@theskinnyscoop.com).
